{"data":{"site":{"pathPrefix":"/restaurant-inspections"},"postgres":{"establishment":[{"establishmentid":"4930","name":"Great Lakes Coffee Beanery","address":"311 Mack Ave","zipcode":"48201","owner":"Dennis Zoma","licenseNumber":"081263","licenseType":"Fixed Establishment","establishmentType":"Food Service Establishment","establishmentStatus":"Permanently Closed","riskCategory":"Medium","reviewFrequencyDays":"365.0","coords":"-83.05466,42.34886","geojson":{"id":"4930","type":"Feature","geometry":{"type":"Point","coordinates":[-83.0546608609999,42.348856239]},"properties":{"name":"Great Lakes Coffee Beanery","owner":"Dennis Zoma","address":"311 Mack Ave","zipcode":"48201","license_type":"Fixed Establishment","risk_category":"Medium","license_number":"081263","establishmentid":"4930","establishment_type":"Food Service Establishment","establishment_status":"Permanently Closed","review_frequency_days":"365.0","most_recent_license_date":"4/24/2017"}},"nearbyList":[{"establishmentid":"808","name":"Detroit Urban League","address":"208 Mack Ave","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"51622697","name":"Chili Mustard Onions","address":"3411 Brush St","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"806","name":"King David Grand Lodge","address":"114 Erskine St","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"3807","name":"Great Lakes Coffee Beanery","address":"3990 John R St","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"5137","name":"Detroit Burger Bar","address":"3990 John R St","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"51622634","name":"Chick-Fil-A","address":"3990 John R St","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"5135","name":"Chiqui Mexican","address":"3990 John R ","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"5198","name":"Bigalora Wood Fired Cucina","address":"3990 John R","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"51622839","name":"Dunkin Donuts OM DMC Donuts","address":"3990 John R St","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"5136","name":"Estia Greek Street Food","address":"3990 John R","zipcode":"48201"}],"inspectionsByEstablishmentidList":[{"inspectionid":"41563","inspectionDate":"2018-02-22T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[]},{"inspectionid":"38101","inspectionDate":"2017-02-21T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"4-702.11","violationDescription":"UTENSILS and FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be SANITIZED before use after cleaning. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Clean utensil(s) and food-contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not sanitized","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"Lack of Sanitizer","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Equipment/utensils must be sanitized after cleaning."},{"violationCode":"4-602.11","violationDescription":"(A) Equipment FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned:     \r\n  (1) Except as specified in ¶ (B) of this section, before each use with a different   type of raw animal FOOD such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, or POULTRY; (P)   \r\n  (2) Each time there is a change from working with raw FOODS to working with   READY-TO-EAT FOODS; (P)   \r\n  (3) Between uses with raw fruits and vegetables and with POTENTIALLY   HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD);   (P)   \r\n  (4) Before using or storing a FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING   DEVICE; (P) and   \r\n  (5) At any time during the operation when contamination may have occurred. (P)\r\n(B) Subparagraph (A)(1) of this section does not apply if the FOOD-CONTACT SURFACE or UTENSIL is in contact with a succession of different raw animal FOODS each requiring a higher cooking temperature as specified under § 3-401.11 than the previous FOOD, such as preparing raw FISH followed by cutting raw poultry on the same cutting board.   \r\n(C) Except as specified in ¶ (D) of this section, if used with POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD), EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned throughout the day at least every 4 hours. (P)   \r\n(D) Except when dry cleaning methods are used as specified under § 4-603.11, surfaces of UTENSILS and EQUIPMENT contacting FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be cleaned:     \r\n  (1)   At any time when contamination may have occurred;\r\n  (2)   At least every 24 hours for iced tea dispensers and CONSUMER self-service UTENSILS such as tongs, scoops, or ladles;\r\n  (3) Before restocking CONSUMER self-service EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS such as condiment dispensers and display containers; and\r\n  (4) In EQUIPMENT such as ice bins and BEVERAGE dispensing nozzles and   enclosed components of EQUIPMENT such as ice makers, cooking oil storage   tanks and distribution lines, BEVERAGE and syrup dispensing lines or tubes,   coffee bean grinders, and water vending EQUIPMENT:\r\n     (a) At a frequency specified by the manufacturer, or\r\n     (b) Absent manufacturer specifications, at a frequency necessary to preclude      accumulation of soil or mold.","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Food-contact surface(s) and utensil(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"After any contamination","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"Ice scoop","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean as specified above."},{"violationCode":"2-301.14","violationDescription":"FOOD EMPLOYEES shall clean their hands and exposed portions of their arms as specified under § 2-301.12 immediately before engaging in FOOD preparation including working with exposed FOOD, clean EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS, and unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES (P) and:\r\n(A)     After touching bare human body parts other than clean hands and clean, exposed portions of arms; (P)\r\n(B)     After using the toilet room; (P)\r\n(C)     After caring for or handling SERVICE ANIMALS or aquatic animals as specified in ¶ 2-403.11(B); (P).\r\n(D)     Except as specified in ¶ 2-401.11(B), after coughing, sneezing, using a handkerchief or disposable tissue, using tobacco, eating, or drinking; (P)\r\n(E)     After handling soiled EQUIPMENT or UTENSILS; (P)\r\n(F)     During FOOD preparation, as often as necessary to remove soil and contamination and to prevent cross contamination when changing tasks; (P)\r\n(G)     When switching between working with raw FOOD and working with READY-TO-EAT FOOD; (P)\r\n(H)     Before donning gloves for working with FOOD; (P) and\r\n(I)      After engaging in other activities that contaminate the hands. (P)","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Employee(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Did not wash hands","subProblem":" after touching bare human body parts other than clean hands/arms","location":"EMPLOYEE(S)","subLocation":"Lack of HAND WASHING","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Hands shall be washed with hot water and soap for at least 20 seconds"},{"violationCode":"3-101.11","violationDescription":"FOOD shall be safe, unADULTERATED and honestly presented. (P)\r\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Food","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Dishonestly presented","subProblem":"","location":"COOLER","subLocation":"EXPIRED DATE MARKING","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":"2017-02-21T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard"},{"violationCode":"4-302.14","violationDescription":"A test kit or other device that accurately measures the concentration in mg/L of SANITIZING solutions shall be provided. (Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Sanitizer test kit","subItem":"chlorine","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"Lack of Test strips","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide as required"},{"violationCode":"2-103.11","violationDescription":"The PERSON IN CHARGE shall ensure that employees, practices and policies are in compliance with the code. (Pf) \r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not ensuring compliance","subProblem":"","location":"PERSON IN CHARGE","subLocation":"In the Facility","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Person-in-charge must ensure compliance with items listed above."},{"violationCode":"6-301.12","violationDescription":"Each HANDWASHING SINK or group of adjacent HANDWASHING SINKS shall be provided with:\r\n(A) Individual, disposable towels; (Pf)\r\n(B) A continuous towel system that supplies the user with a clean towel;(Pf) or \r\n(C) A heated-air hand drying device.(Pf)\r\n(D) A hand drying device that employs an air-knife system that delivers high velocity pressurized air at ambient temperatures.(Pf)\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Sanitary hand drying provisions","subItem":"disposable, paper towels","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"Lack of Paper toweling","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide adequate sanitary hand drying aids/devices."},{"violationCode":"4-301.12","violationDescription":"(A) Except as specified in ¶ (C) of this section, a sink with at least 3 compartments shall be provided for manually washing, rinsing, and SANITIZING EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS. (Pf)   \r\n(B) Sink compartments shall be large enough to accommodate immersion of the largest EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS. If EQUIPMENT or UTENSILS are too large for the WAREWASHING sink, a WAREWASHING machine or alternative EQUIPMENT as specified in ¶ (C) of this section shall be used. (Pf)\r\n(C) Before a 2-compartment sink is used the PERMIT HOLDER shall have its use APPROVED.\r\n(D) A 2-compartment sink may not be used for WAREWASHING operations where cleaning and SANITIZING solutions are used for a continuous or intermittent flow of KITCHENWARE or TABLEWARE in an ongoing WAREWASHING process.\r\n\r\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Three compartment sink","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"Lack of Three Compartment sink set-up","corrected":"No","daysToCorrect":"10.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide as required"},{"violationCode":"3-304.12","violationDescription":"During pauses in FOOD preparation or dispensing, UTENSILS shall be stored:\r\n(A) In the FOOD with their handles above the top of the FOOD and the container;\r\n(B) In FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS with their handles above the      top of the FOOD within containers or EQUIPMENT that can be closed, such as      bins of sugar, flour, or cinnamon;\r\n(C) On a clean portion of the FOOD preparation table or cooking EQUIPMENT\r\n(D)  In running water, such as dipper well.\r\n(E)  In a clean, protected location if the UTENSILS, such as ice scoops, are   used only with a FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS; or\r\n(F)  In a container of water maintained at a temperature of at least 135° F.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Dispensing utensil(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Improperly stored","subProblem":"To prevent contamination of food or food related items","location":"HANDSINK(S)","subLocation":"Ice scoop","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2017-02-21T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store in manner that does not contaminate items"},{"violationCode":"4-903.11","violationDescription":"Cleaned EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS, laundered LINENS, and SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES shall be stored in an approved manner and location.\r\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Clean equipment/utensil(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored in soiled, wet conditions","subProblem":"","location":"PREP AREA(S)","subLocation":"On the Counter(s)","corrected":"Yes","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":"2017-02-21T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store in protected manner."},{"violationCode":"MFL289.2129","violationDescription":"Sec. 2129. (1) All of the following food establishments shall employ a minimum of 1 managerial employee who is currently certified under a personnel certification program accredited by the American national standards institute, utilizing the conference for food protection standards:  (a) A food service establishment that is not any of the following:    (i) Operating under a temporary food service establishment license.  (ii) A vending machine location.     (b) An extended retail food establishment.  (c) Operated within a retail grocery.  (2) An individual certified under subsection (1) shall be recognized with full faith and credit by the state and all local units of government throughout the state.  (3) The department may promulgate rules to do all of the following:  (a) Develop requirements for retail food establishments to follow when employing certified food safety managers or personnel.  (b) Set a reasonable date for compliance with the requirements under subdivision (a) taking into consideration existing local personnel certification requirements.  (c) Establish certification fees necessary to implement, maintain, and track certified individuals directly or by contract. The department may annually adjust the schedule of fees to provide that the fee charged is sufficient to cover the cost of the certification tracking program.  (d) Implement and enforce the requirements described in subdivision (a).    (4) The certification program developed by the American national standards institute, as it exists on April 1, 2008 , is incorporated by reference. The department may adopt updates to the certification program accreditation standards in subsection (1) by rule.     (5) This section does not prohibit any local legislative body from implementing a food handler program, an employee health certification program, or a manager certification program, if it is not in conflict with this section.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"PERSON IN CHARGE","subLocation":"In the Facility","corrected":"Not required","daysToCorrect":"30.0","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide"}]}]}]}},"pageContext":{"eid":"4930"}}